DARREN SCHMIDT

Austin, TX 78735 | Phone: 480-773-4657 | Email: dschmidt220@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/dschmidt220

SUMMARY

Solutions-savvy UX Researcher helping teams develop world class user experiences. Thrives on creating compelling user experiences to improve brand loyalty, customer retention, and deliver delightment. Excellent communication and effectively collaborates with others to ensure goals are achieved.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

UX/UI: Affinity Diagramming, Journey Maps, Wireframing, User Testing, User Empathy, Comparative Analysis, Qualitative and Quantitative Research Methods, Data Analysis, Adobe XD, Sketch, InVision, HTML, CSS

Other: Educational Technology, Public Speaking, Presentations, Collaboration, Project Management, Slack

viewpoints and designed experience improvements for collaborative product team solutions.

EXPERIENCE

Customer Experience Abrams Learning Trends

2017 – 2018 Austin. TX

Created compelling customer experiences for users of digital products and K-12 program materials.

Conducted customer research interviews for user experiences. Managed projects to assess customer

Learning Specialist Macmillan Learning

2016 - 2017

Austin, TX

Recognized by manager for exceeding KPI metrics in territory accounts to demonstrate the pedagogical
effectiveness of student response systems (classroom i-clickers) for university and college faculty.
Collaborated effectively with cross-functional teams for product developments.

Teacher Kyrene School District

1999 - 2015

Phoenix, AZ

 Generated an on site digital database of instructional lessons and strategies for effective professional development. Collaborated and strategized with faculty for student success through forward-thinking educational technology solutions.

EDUCATION

UX/UI Bootcamp Certificate: University of Texas, McCombs School of Business, Austin, TX

Master of Education, Educational Technology: Northern Arizona University, Flagstaff, AZ

Bachelor of Arts, Social Sciences: Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ